Sean Welsh Brown Full-Stack Web Developer / Engineer

Brooklyn, NY 11201 | 908-967-0525 | seanwelshbrown@gmail.com Portfolio: www.seanwelshbrown.com / Social: Github | LinkedIn | Dev | Medium

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced in JavaScript, React JS, Redux, Gatsby JS, HTML, CSS and Ruby on Rails, with an ability to quickly parse, learn and implement new technical information. Over a decade of professional experience as an Actor and Voice-Over artist has made me highly skilled in public speaking, problem solving, collaboration, communication, and meeting / exceeding project deadlines. Knowledgeable in Windows, Mac and Linux development environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React JS, Redux, Gatsby JS, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL (PostgreSQL)

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Focus - Front-End | Back-End | hosted: https://focus-timer.app/

A Meditation and Focus wellness app, prioritizing an organic UX, minimalism, and productivity.

- Built front-end using **React JS**, **Redux** and **custom CSS**; prioritized clean, DRY code and comments.
- Developed a Rails API back-end with routes for authenticated Users and saved Meditation/Focus sessions.
- Utilized Moment.js and external APIs for a dynamic, informational home page.

The Fractal Zone - Front-End | Back-End | hosted: https://thefractal.zone/

An interactive graphical application to generate and save custom geometric fractal designs.

- Built front-end using **React JS** and **custom CSS**.
- Developed a Rails API back-end with routes for Users and saved Fractal designs
- Utilized **P5.is** to create a responsive HTML5 canvas to render designs.
- Implemented User authentication and authorization, displaying saved designs in a gallery along with other users.

Today - Front-End/Back-End | hosted: https://liaowow.github.io/today-frontend/

A personal journaling app to archive daily moods and thoughts.

- Built front-end in vanilla JavaScript, using only native features to strengthen fundamentals.
- Utilized **Bootstrap** framework for styling.
- Developed a Rails API back-end to persist user entries and moods, and do additional logic to render mood trends.

EXPERIENCE

CESD Talent New York, New York 02/ 2009 - Present

Actor / Voice-Over Narrator

- Narrated TV/radio campaigns for: *Microsoft, Avis, McDonalds, + more.*
- Narrated educational software and audiobooks for: Scholastic, Harper, Audible, + more.
- Worked both remote and in-person on recording contracts, deepening knowledge of audio software + Windows and Mac operating systems.
- Performed practices on tight deadlines, communicated directly with clients to develop personalized approaches to commercial projects.

John Marshall Media New York, New York

Voice Talent 10/ 2015 - 01/ 2020 Collaborated with a team of engineers and directors on multiple audiobooks and educational software; partnered on

EDUCATION

sound and recording best practices for respective projects.

Flatiron School Brooklyn, New York JavaScript, React JS, HTML / CSS and Ruby on Rails immersive software engineering program 12/2019 - 03/2020

New York University New York, New York Bachelor of Fine Arts in Theatre: GPA: 3.6 05/2014

Minor in Web Programming and Applications